Finding Aid for the Walter J. Harrelson Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Hyatt Anniversary, 2/16/74 (Box 25, Folder 25)
- Hebrew-English Pocket Dictionary Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 26)
- Biblical Perspectives on Worship, Greenlake (Box 25, Folder 27)
- Biblical and Historical Roots of Prisons (Box 25, Folder 28)
- Pastors School- University of Richmond, 6/24-6/27 (Box 25, Folder 29)
- Ecumenical Evangelism Conference 8/19/68-8/23/68, Chicago (Box 25, Folder 30)
- North Park Theological Seminary, Nov 10-12, 1969, Chicago (Box 25, Folder 31)
- Isaiah Lectures (Box 25, Folder 32)
- Secularization and the Bible (Box 25, Folder 33)
- Biblical Theology and Contemporary Exegesis- Cole Lectures VU (Box 25, Folder 34)
- Christian Higher Education- Lecture (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Lectures- Acts Seattle Convention (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Georgetown College- Lectures on Prophets, 8/7/72-8/11/72 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- “ana yasi” (Box 25, Folder 4)
- Lectures- Amos (Box 25, Folder 5)
- The Annotated Bible- Malachi (Box 25, Folder 6)
- The Apostle Paul speaks to his fellow Christians (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Baptism (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Bara Humbert Article (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Worship Lectures- Pittsburgh, 6/7/71-6/10/71 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Bible and Man’s place in society- Lectures (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Biblical Faith and the College Campus (Box 25, Folder 12)
- Biblical Faith in the Age of Technology (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Biblical Mandate to Evangelize the world, Notre Dame, Summary to Norgren by, May 25 (Box 25, Folder 14)
- Biblical Research and the New Criticism (Box 25, Folder 15)
- Hebrew Faith and Culture, Oxford University Press, Correspondence (Box 25, Folder 16)
- Heilsgeschichte and the OT Canon (Box 25, Folder 17)
- Highway Deaths and Public Transport (Box 25, Folder 18)
- The Immanuel Sign in Context “Technology Today” (Box 25, Folder 19)
- Historical Jesus and Christology (Box 25, Folder 20)
- Lectures- Hosea (Box 25, Folder 21)
- How to Teach the Bible (Box 25, Folder 22)
- The Icon and Ecumenicity (Box 25, Folder 23)
- Indicative and Imperative in the Mission of the Church (Box 25, Folder 24)
- Lectures- Isaiah (Box 25, Folder 25)
- Israel and the Christ (Box 25, Folder 26)
- Israelite and Christian Worship (Box 25, Folder 27)
- The J&E Materials (Box 25, Folder 28)
- “Jewish-Christian Relations”, 3/15/67 (Box 25, Folder 29)
- Judaism and Christianity Materials (Box 25, Folder 30)
- King and Servant in the Biblical Faith (Box 25, Folder 31)
- The Church and Church Holidays (Box 25, Folder 32)
- Probation and Reality Project (Box 26, Folder 33)
- Interfaith Association- Charting Event, 4/26/82 (Box 26, Folder 34)
- Institute for African/Afro-American Religions (Box 26, Folder 35)
- Gospel and Acts (Box 26, Folder 36)
- Prophets (Box 26, Folder 37)
- Prophets (Box 26, Folder 1)
- West End Church – Lectures (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Bible (Box 26, Folder 3)
- Old Testament- Genesis – Solomon’s Song (Box 26, Folder 4)
- Ruach in the Qumran I Materials 1/57 (Box 26, Folder 5)
- Spirit in the DSS (Box 26, Folder 6)
- Spirit in the Bible (Box 26, Folder 7)
- EStravinsky’s symphony of Psalms (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Theological view of History and Change- Foundations (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Reviews (Box 26, Folder 10)
- Bibliography, March 1958 (Box 26, Folder 11)
- Reviews, 1967-1968 (Box 27, Folder 12)
- Hyatt Festschrift (Box 27, Folder 13)
- Paper- The Church and Israel (Box 27, Folder 14)
- Britannica Article (Box 27, Folder 15)
- Spirit and Holy Spirit (Box 27, Folder 16)
- God’s Purpose for the Church- Religion in Life (Box 27, Folder 17)
- Good Enough Jubilee Volume, Jan 1, 1966 (Box 27, Folder 18)
- Prophecy and Syncretism- ANTS Bulletin, March 1964 (Box 27, Folder 19)
- May Festschrift- Cosmology (Box 27, Folder 20)
- Fall of Jerusalem Sept 1965 IAHR (Box 27, Folder 21)
- Non-Royal Motifs in the Royal Eschatology (Box 27, Folder 22)
- Daniel- Study Guide, Methodist Church, 8/17/64 (Box 27, Folder 23)
- Worship Volume- Doubleday (Box 27, Folder 24)
- NCC- Evangelism Paper (Box 27, Folder 25)
- “Exodus”- Crossroads, 3/1/66 (Box 27, Folder 26)
- Deuteronomy- Samuel- Adult Teacher (Box 27, Folder 27)
- Jeremiah Manuscript Pub., 1959 (Box 27, Folder 28)
- The Kingdoms of Israel and Judah, Jun 1, 1965 (Box 27)
- The Biblical Concept of the Free Man (Box 27)
- Christian Century- Nat. Purpose and Ancient Vision (empty) (Box 27)
- Meditation on the Resurrection, Power, July-Sept 1964 (Box 27)
- Emory Conference, 11/18/65-11/20/65 (Box 27)
- Interpreter’s Dictionary of the Bible (Box 27)
- Interpreter’s Dictionary of the Bible, Due, March 1, 1959 (Box 27)
- Wisdom and Pastoral Theology (Box 27)
- ARK (Box 27)
- Council, Counsel, The Council and Council House 600 (Box 27)
- Golden Calf 1000 (Box 27)
- Ceremonial Law 10 (Box 27)
- Decree 20 (Box 27)
- Honor, OT and NT 500 (Box 27)
- Testimony 200 (Box 27)
- Commandment(s) 100 (Box 27)
- Court of Law 250 words (Box 27)
- Obeisance 50 words (Box 27)
- Poison 750 (Box 27)
- Walls 40 (Box 27)
- Covenant, Book of 50 (Box 27)
- Molech (Box 27)
- Ten Commandments 3000 (Box 27)
- Torah 150 (Box 27)
- Law-OT 10000 (Box 27)
- Stranger (Box 27)
- Doubleday, Anchor- Shechem (Box 27)
- Humanists and Public Policy (Box 27)
- Creative Spirit in OT, 2 Samuel, 23 1-7 (Box 27)
- Covenant- Methodist Article (Box 27)
- 2 Esdras Article, Silberman (Box 27)
- Methodist Article in “Biblical Literature” Due, 11/15/80 (Box 27)
- I Met a Man Named Jesus (Box 27)
- Jeremiah (Box 27)
- Father Ryan High School- Retreat- St. Mary’s Villa, Jan 26, 1983 (Box 28)
- Helps from the OT (Box 28)
- Perspectives from the Hebrew Bible on Prophecy, wisdom, prayer (Box 28)
- “The Prophetic message and Public responsibility in Christian Education” Scarritt, 4/14/83 (Box 28)
- The OT and Unity (Box 28)
- Ten Commandments Lecture (Box 28)
- God’s Reign in the Prophets (Box 28)
- Problem of Bible Authority- Commentary, 1981 (Box 28)
- Leadership and Learning (Box 28)
- Scholarship in the Service of Teaching (Box 28)
- “How Old and New Prophets Deal with Politics (Box 28)
- Prayer and the Practicing Minister (Box 28)
- ASSR Paper- Methodology in the Analysis of Israelite Prophetic eschatology (Box 28)
- Recent Manuscript Discoveries (Box 28)
- Henderson, Kentucky, 4/25/82-4/26/82 (Box 28)
- Meaning of Zion in Jewish and Christian Hope (Box 28)
- Method in the Analysis of Prophetic Eschatology (Box 28)
- “Prophetic Eschatology: Its Continuing Significance for the Christian Community Today” H. May Manuel Lecture, Oberlin, 1980 (Box 28)
- Ten Commandments- in Bible and Today (Box 28)
- Wooster-Deuteronomy 4 Lecture, 3/3/81 (Box 28)
- Oklahoma Trip (Box 28)
- The SBL: An Assessment of its Influence (Box 28)
- Star Island- “Religion in an age of Science” Conference, July 261980-Aug 2, 1980 (Box 28)
- Tullahoma Meditation, 3/27-3/28 (Box 28)
- Human Rights- Monday Nights (Box 28)
- “The Meaning of Israel for Christians” Knoxville NCCJ 4/25 (Box 28)
- Religious Model of the Person (Box 28)
- Biblical Faith and Contemporary Dilemmas (Box 28)
- Huffman, United Methodist Church, Birmingham (Box 28)
- Bultmann (Box 28)
- Birmingham Lecture, 12/29/76 (Box 28)
- Birmingham NCCJ, 4/10/80 (Box 28)
- Century 3 Session- Religion in Nashville (Box 28)
- Basic Beliefs of the People of the Book, Judaism, Christianity and Islam (Box 28)
- Pamela Owens Ordination (Box 28)
- Wisdom- 2nd Presbyterian Church (Box 28)
- SBL Paper 79 Post-exilic Theology (Box 28)
- Lectures- OT Studies and Christian Minister (Box 28)
- Importance of Shechem in Hebrew Religious Traditions (Box 28)
- Priesthood in the Bible- Lectures (Box 28)
- Religions and the Doctrine of the Spirit, Roger Williams Fellowship 1959 (Box 28)
- Translation of Rudolph, Jeremia (Box 28)
- Lectures- 7 Words of Jesus (Box 28)
- Shadow of Cross in OT- Lecture (Box 28)
- Southern Protestantism (Box 28)
- Vatican City/Council (Box 28)
- OT Worship (Box 28)
- Human Sexuality- Lectures (Box 28)
- Hebrew Language and Israelite faith- McAllaster (Box 28)
- Colossians (Box 28)
- Luther Seminary Papers (Box 28)
- Intertestamental Literature Lectures, Eau Claire, 11/12/76-11/13/76 (Box 28)
- Wake Forest Lectures (Box 28)
- Marikawa- Address by W. Harrelson (Box 28)
- Mars Hill Trip (Box 28)
- Biblical Research and the New Criticism (Box 28)
- Zealot Papers- C.B. Anderson (Box 28)
- Survey of American Protestant Thought (Box 28)
- Typological Interpretation of the OT (Box 28)
- Ways of Communication in the Bible Bossey 3/26/63, other WCC Correspondence (Box 28)
- World Come of Age- 5 Lectures (Box 28)
- Worship and the Shape of Life in Old Israel (Box 28)
- Worship in a New Age 2/15/65-2/16/65 UCC Springfield, Mass. (Box 28)
- Worship in a Theological Community (Box 28)
- Lectures- Zechariah (Box 28)
- Card Catalogue Key (Box 28)
- Life in the Bible- Lectures (Box 28)
- Lordship of Christ- Lecture (Box 28)
- Lecture- Man in the OT (Box 28)
- Ministers Sacred and Profane (Box 28)
- Nature of Church in Light of Scripture (Box 28)
- The Negro and Theological Education (Box 28)
- OT and Art (Box 28)
- ANTS- Pastoral Theology Lectures, July 1965 (Box 28)
- OT and Tradition- SBL (Box 29)
- Ten Commandments Manuscript (Box 29)
- Overtures (Box 29)
- Psalm 90- Rylaarsdam Festschrift (Box 29)
- Judah’s Later History- Methodist (Box 29)
- Patient Love in the Testament of Joseph (Box 29)
- Research in the OT, 1948 -JBR (Box 29)
- “Shechem in Extra-Biblical References” (Box 29)
- Baptist Leader-Worship Suggestions June 1957 (Box 29)
- Bible Words for Today (Box 29)
- Abilmelech- Encyclopedia Britannica (Box 29)
- Baptist Leader “From Preacher to Pastoral Director?” (Box 29)
- Biblical Studies- In Theological Curriculum and Church (Box 29)
- Encyclopedia Britannica Articles- Matthews, Shailer, etc. (Box 29)
- Creation- Christian Scholar (Box 29)
- Article for Interpretation, 9/1/75 (Box 29)
- The Idea of Agape in the OT (Box 29)
- Guide to the OT (Box 29)
- Decalogue (Box 29)
- Fact and Implication in the DSS “Christianity and Crisis” (Box 29)
- “The Biblical Basis of the Gospel” Watchman-Examiner (Box 29)
- Elisha, Ezekiel –Encyclopedia Americana (Box 29)
- “Biblical Faith and Rural Life” Town and Country Church (Box 29)
- Art for Children’s Religion- “OT Persons as people worth knowing” (Box 29)
- “The Bible and Creation” Children’s Religion (Box 29)
- “The Human side of the DSS- Advance (Box 29)
- Some Major Terms for the church in the NT, Foundations, April 1958 (Box 29)
- Christian Century March- April 1958, Lenten Editorials (Box 29)
- DSS- Britannica, Book of the Year, October 15, 1957 (Box 29)
- Advance article- “Biblical Theology in the Church” (Box 29)
- Barth on the Decalogue (Box 29)
- Theology of Tradition- Knight book (Box 29)
- On God’s Knowledge of self (Box 29)
- Catalyst Tapes (Box 29)
- Famine/ Biblical Judgments and Promises (Box 29)
- Worship Manuscripts (Box 29)
- OT Theology- Beginning with Creation (Box 30)
- OT Theology- Faith and Culture (Box 30)
- Psalm Classification (Box 30)
- OT Theology- V. Rod Approach (Box 30)
- Mari (Box 30)
- Pottery (Box 30)
- Phoenician, Aramaic, and Palestinian Inscriptions (Box 30)
- OT Canon and Text-1950 Lecture Notes (Box 30)
- Akkadian-Ugaritic Texts, etc (Box 30)
- Job (Box 30)
- Ezekiel (Box 30)
- Archeology and OT (Box 30)
- OT 357- Jeremiah-Proposed topics for special study (Box 30)
- Bibliography on Textual History of the OT (Box 30)
- OT 410- OT Textual History (Box 30)
- Apocryphal Literature (Box 30)
- Jewish-Christian Relations: The First Six Centuries (Box 30)
- Jewish-Christian Relations: The First Century (Box 30)
- Boston- Jewish-Christian Workshop (Box 30)
- All Saints, 7/10/83 (Box 30)
- Bairnwick, 7/7/83 (Box 30)
- Hiram College, April 20-21, 1983 (Box 30)
- Proclamation, 7/12/83-7/14/83 (Box 30)
- Psalm 42 (Multiple Copies) (Box 30)
- Pharisees (Box 30)
- Food and Population Class, 11/3/76 (Box 30)
- Religion and Worship of Ancient Israel (Box 30)
- Pentateuch (Box 30)
- Rhetorical Criticism- Israelite Worship- Class Notes (Box 30)
- Religion 300- Methods of Biblical Criticism (Box 30)
- Sin/Grace- Sewanee (Box 30)
- Div 222- OT Introduction (Box 30)
- Genesis Hebrew notes (Box 30)
- Nabum, Habakkuk, Obadiah (Box 30)
- Prophets Outline (Box 30)
- Huntsville- OT course, 1966-1967 (Box 30)
- Ezra, Nehemiah, Chronicles (Box 30)
- ANE Bibliography (Box 30)
- Persian Religion (Box 30)
- Bibliography of Jeremiah (Box 30)
- OT 357- Jeremiah –Hebrew Exegesis (Box 30)
- PSR Course-PSS (Box 31)
- Phi Beta Kappa Lecture, 11/4/76 (Box 31)
- Promise on way to Consummation (Box 31)
- Transcendence- Clergy Conference Monteagle, 9/10/74 (Box 31)
- College Lectures on OT- Shahan, Ewing (Box 31)
- Jewish Literature and Thought in Post-Exilic Period: Realities and Ideologies, Introduction to Judaism 6/17/75 VDS (Box 31)
- Biblical Prayer: Critique and Resource for Praying Today (Box 31)
- Religion and Politics in the Bible (Box 31)
- II Esdras- Lecture: Will Many Be Saved? (Box 31)
- Creation/ Saving History (Box 31)
- Biblical Archeology, 1966 (Box 31)
- Jeremiah Manuscript – Muilenburg/Anderson (Box 31)
- Text- Moses (Box 31)
- Reports- Div School Special Events (Box 31)
- SBL- 100th Anniversary Committee (Box 31)
- SBL Awards- Copy for Printer (Box 31)
- Christianity, Worship, etc- Christianity in our days (Box 31)
- SBL Centennial Banquet program (Multiple Copies) (Box 31)
- Epistles (Box 31)
- Awards Committee, SBL Centennial (Box 31)
- Official Copy of Program and of Awards Citations (Box 31)
- Nominations- SBL Awards (Box 31)
- W. Harrelson Addresses- 1971 V.U. Baccalaureate and Div School Commencement (Box 31)
- Sermons- Addresses Tantur (Box 31)
- The Ministry and Sacraments Committee, etc. (Box 31)
- Huntsville, May 20, 1982 (Box 31)
- Continuing Education- Jackson Tennessee- Sermons, May 20 and June 10 (Box 31)
- Sermons, Talks (Box 31)
- Prayers- Commencement and Baccalaureate (Box 31)
- Faith and History in the Red Sea Narrative (Box 32)
- Genesis and Biblical Faith (Box 32)
- Scared Acts and Seasons (Box 32)
- Dictionary of Southern Religion “Theological Education” (Box 32)
- Messianic Hope in Judaism (Box 32)
- Christian Misreading of Basic Themes in the Hebrew Scriptures (Box 32)
- The Prophetic Eschatological Visions and the Kingdom of Go (Box 32)
- Temptation and Faithfulness of God (Box 32)
- On God’s Care of the Earth, Psalm 104 (Box 32)
- “Our Approach to the Bible” – in Bible in Our Home (Box 32)
- NAB Article (Box 32)
- Development in OT Research 1970-1980 St. Luke’s Journal of Theology, June 1980 (Box 32)
- Fertility Cult Worship (Box 32)
- Childs- Introduction to OT as Scripture- Review for JBL, 3/1/80 (Box 32)
- Genesis Book (Box 32)
- Ten Commandments- Contract with Fortress Press (Box 32)
- Ten Commandments- Contract with Fortress Press (Box 32)
- Ecumenism in Jerusalem- Cullman Festschrift (Box 32)
- Orlinsky Volume- IEJ: Trial of the High Priest Joshua (Box 32)
- Is the Bible True? Methodist Article, 2/3/82 (Box 32)
- The Theology of Numbers –Interpretive (Box 32)
- Hastings Dictionary of the Bible –Revision of, Dec 1958 (Box 32)
- Hithyatsebh -Worship in Early Israel (Box 32)
- “Manuscripts and Peoples at the Judean Desert” Religion in Life (Box 32)
- The Book of Ecoles Article (Box 32)
- Kierkegaard and Abraham (Box 32)
- Interpreting the OT (Box 32)
- Vengeance- OT and NT (Box 32)
- Blessing and Cursing (Box 32)
- “The Religion of Israel” Companion to the Bible (Box 32)
- Revelation and the Prophets of Israel- Crozer- Voice 60:1, January 1968 4-6, 17 (Box 32)
- Prophets- Encyclopedia Britannica, 9/1/60 (Box 32)
- Biblical Understanding of Spirituality (Box 32)
- The Christian Congregation and the Bicentennial- SLJT (Box 32)
- Pulpit- God’s Sovereignty (Box 32)
- “The Prophets and God’s Coming Rule” SE Baptist Seminary- The Outlook (Box 32)
- Holiness- OT and NT (Box 32)
- Images (Box 32)
- Queen of Heaven (Box 32)
- Bonhoeffer and the Bible (Box 32)
- Worship- OT and NT- 1200 HDB (Box 32)
- Encyclopedia Britannica- Joshua-, Nov 1, 1960 (Box 32)
- Annotations to I Esdras- Oxford University Press (Box 32)
- Reviews, 1965-66 (Box 32)
- Reviews, 1963-64 (Box 32)
- Reviews, 1960-62 (Box 32)
- Harrelson, 1959, Reviews (Box 32)
- Reviews, 1958 (Box 32)
- Reviews, 1957 (Box 32)
- Reviews, 1956 (Box 32)
- Reviews- 1955 and earlier (Box 32)
- Academy of Spiritual Formation (Box 33)
- American Jewish Committee 10/31/87 Atlanta (Box 33)
- Georgetown Institute, 6/18/90-/6/22/90 (Box 33)
- 2/18-2/28 Israel- Balto Group (Box 33)
- Institute of Medicine, 10/11/89 (Box 33)
- Jerusalem Tour, July/Aug 1990 (Box 33)
- Jerusalem- Hartman Institute, 5/27/90-/5/30/90 (Box 33)
- Land in Tanakh (Box 33)
- Methodist Video 11/13/90-Script (Box 33)
- NEH – Dictionary Grant (Box 33)
- GE’EZ Bible- NEH Grant (Box 33)
- NEH- GE’EZ Bible (Box 33)
- Northwestern University, 2/7/90-2/9/90 (Box 33)
- Oxford Companion to the Bible (Box 33)
- RSV- Special Works, 1984 (Box 33)
- Jack Sharp- Balto 3/18/91/ Lecture Text- Good Friday (Box 33)
- RSV- Video Project (Box 33)
- Unification Theological Seminary, 5/21-5/22 (Box 33)
- Wake Forest, 5/2/88-5/4/88 (Box 33)
- Adrian, MI, 1/24/92-1/26/92 (Box 34)
- Kanuga, 1/9/92-1/11/92 (Box 34)
- Jerusalem- Then, Now and To Be (Box 34)
- Australia- Aug- September Evansville, 10/25-10/27 (Box 34)
- TCU 11/29, 11/30, 12/1 (Box 34)
- Methodist Youth- 5/10 Hebrew Bible and Christianity (Box 34)
- Martin Methodist College 4/8 (Box 34)
- NRSV- Prism, 1/15/91 (Box 34)
- Light Motifs in Christianity (Box 34)
- Wild Acres, North Carolina, 8/5-8/8 (Box 34)
- Jewish/Christian Relations Book (Box 34)
- 4/2- Austin Peay University (Box 34)
- UT Chattanooga- Jim Smalley, 5/6-5/7 (Box 34)
- 1st Presbyterian Nashville 4/3, 4/7 4/24, 5/1, and 5/8 (Box 34)
- 8/12/91-8/15/91 Ohio (Box 34)
- Feminist Response to the Bible 4/23 (Box 34)
- SBL/ NABPR- Atlanta, 3/4/91-3/16/91 (Box 34)
- Death Penalty (Box 34)
- Gallatin- High School Study 4/25 (Box 34)
- Lecture on the Psalms 4/30 Scarritt- Bennett (Box 34)
- TCU- Purdue, April 1991 (Box 34)
- Wheeling, West Virginia and Pittsburgh, 3/18-3/20 (Box 34)
- Jacksonville, Florida- Ten Commandments, 2/3/91-2/7/91 (Box 34)
- Book Publicity and Meeting (Box 34)
- Holocaust- MTSU, April 11-12 (Box 34)
- CROS-NRSV, 10/15-10/17 (Box 34)
- Carbondale, IL, 10/20-10/21 (Box 34)
- Evansville, IN, 10/18-10/19/1998 (Box 34)
- Wooster- Psalms- 10/17 (Box 34)
- Trinity Methodist, Southport (Box 34)
- Union Congregation Church, 9/15-9/16 (Box 34)
- Civil Rights Diary (Box 34)
- RSV Article- Princeton Bulletin, 7/1/90 (Box 34)
- Book Manuscript- “Judaism and Christianity” (Box 34)
- Denver July 17, NRSV (Box 34)
- Mercer Dictionary (Box 34)
- Loose- Mercer Dictionary (Box 34)
- Loose- Book Reviews- Christians and Jews (Box 35)
- Ten Commandments Article For F. Cloud (Box 35)
- 1st Lutheran- Geography and Faith (Box 35)
- Westminster Presbyterian (Box 35)
- 1st Presbyterian- Franklin 10/28 and 11/14 (Box 35)
- Exegesis- Pluralism (Box 35)
- Book Fair, 11/12/90 (Box 35)
- Minneapolis- Spiritual Formation, 11/10/91-11/15/91 (Box 35)
- West End United Methodist- “Jesus and Christians”, 11/7, 11/14, 11/28,12/5, and 12/12 (Box 35)
- Bloomington- UCC on NRSV, 6/25/90-6/29/90 (Box 35)
- The Origin of Language According to the Bible (Box 35)
- Lambuth College, 4/20/90-4/21/90 (Box 35)
- Huntsville- Prayer Breakfast (Box 35)
- Spirituality in Hebrew Scriptures (Box 35)
- Chaplains- VDS, 3/15-3/17 (Box 35)
- Our Lady of the Lake 2/26, 3/5, and 3/12 (Box 35)
- Baltimore David Hartman and Walter Harrelson Lecture, 4/30/90 (Box 35)
- Harper’s Encyclopedia of Christian Education (Box 35)
- 1-2 Esdras- Oxford Annotated Bible (Box 35)
- Pleasant Green Baptist Church, 7/8/90 (Box 35)
- Our Lady of the Lake, Hendersonville, 4/8/90 (Box 35)
- SBL-SE Charlotte, 3/16/90-3/18/90 (Box 35)
- Memphis- NRSV, 11/8/91 (Box 35)
- Chicago- National Workshop on Christian/ Jewish Relations, 11/4/90-11/7/90 (Box 35)
- Favorite Bible Passages NRSV (Box 35)
- St. Henry’s- Ten Commandments, 2/4/90 and 2/18/90 (Box 35)
- Vine Street- Torah and Prophets 2/4 and 2/18 (Box 35)
- New Discoveries and Bible Translations (Box 35)
- Andover Newton-Jeremiah, 3/6/90-3/7/90 (Box 35)
- Worship in Ancient Israel (Box 35)
- “Passing on Tradition” 10/19 BSU (Box 35)
- Church of the Nativity, Huntsville 3/7, and 3/14 (Box 35)
- Wesley Seminary Lecture, 3/25/90 (Box 35)
- Memphis 2/11-2/13 Jewish/Christian Relations (Box 35)
- The Temple-Jewish/Christian Relations 12/7 (Box 35)
- Christ Church-Retreat and Sermon (Box 35)
- Temple- Christianity and Judaism, 4/1/90 (Box 35)
- Memphis- Cathedral 2/11 (Box 35)
- Memphis- AIDS, 11/13-11/14 (Box 35)
- St. George’s Church, 10/22/89 (Box 35)
- MDOB Syllabi (Box 35)
- Ethiopia Lecture (Box 35)
- Huntsville 2/25 (Box 35)
- Kittel Lecture- Yale, 10/18/89 (Box 35)
- Montreal Trip, 10/4/89-10/8/89 (Box 35)
- 1st Presbyterian Old Hickory, 10/15/89 (Box 35)
- Macmillan- Encyclopedia of Religion Article (Box 35)
- Mission in the Early Church- Baltimore (Box 35)
- Meyer Festschrift- 1 Corinthians 15 and OT Quotations (Box 35)
- Walter Harrelson Festschrift, 9/21/89 (Box 35)
- Dialogue- Furman 114 (Box 35)
- Decline/ Failure of Prophecy- SBL, 1985 (Box 35)
- Textual and translation Problems in Ester (Box 35)
- ATS Article 9/30 (Box 35)
- Why Christians should study the OT (Box 35)
- VDS Sermon- 4/4 MLK Death Date (Box 35)
- Authority of the Bible- Baptists (Box 35)
- NRSV Book- Metzger, Denton, Walter Harrelson (Box 35)
- Southern Baptist- Bible Authority 10/26-10/27, Birmingham (Box 35)
- Ford Grant- Final Report (Box 36)
- Ford Renewal- Ge’ez Bible (Box 36)
- Ford Foundation Grant Request (Box 36)
- Gutenberg Bible (Box 36)
- Hanhart, Karel (Box 36)
- New Orleans- My Paper (Harrelson)- NRSV (Box 36)
- Harry M. Orlinsky (Box 36)
- Thomas Paine Memorial (Box 36)
- Sergew Project (Box 36)
- Charles Longstreet Weltner (Box 36)
- General Correspondence 83/84 (Box 36)
- NEH Award Letter (Box 36)
- Walter Harrelson Research Council Grant- Summer 1978 and Spring 1981 (Box 36)
- Harrelson Personal (Box 36)
- Apocryphal Article- Oxford (Box 37)
- Reviews- Anchor Bible Dictionary (Box 37)
- Anchor Bible Dictionary- Non- SBL- Wash D.C. (Box 37)
- Andrews University, 10/30-31/94 (Box 37)
- Arab Christianity (Box 37)
- Barr Festschrift (Box 37)
- Baylor University “Psalms” (Box 37)
- Bible and Justice, February 17, 1994- 7:15 pm (Box 37)
- Biblical Grounds for Ethics (Box 37)
- Christian Theological Seminary, 4/27/92 (Box 37)
- Christian Theological Seminary Baccalaureate (honorary degree) (Box 37)
- “Creation” Article (Box 37)
- Disciple Magazine on Jewish/ Christian Relations (Box 37)
- Blenkinsopp Festschrift, 2/15/92 (Box 37)
- Ethiopian Ezra Apocalypse (Box 37)
- Ethiopian Ezra Apocalypse (Box 37)
- Ethiopian Ezra Apocalypse (Box 37)
- Walter Harrelson Article on Eckardt (Box 37)
- Exile Lectures (Box 37)
- Greenberg Festschrift- Summer, 1994 (Box 37)
- San Francisco- Hebrew Bible and Hate (Box 37)
- Hemlock Society (Box 37)
- Hillsboro Presbyterian, Aug 4, 1991 (Box 37)
- Jacksonville, Florida 2/7-11/93 (Christian Enrichment School) (Box 37)
- Jesus and Jewish People (Box 37)
- Jewish/ Christian Relations Talk- Texas Christian University, 10/8/92 (Box 37)
- Journey Through the Bible, 9/1/92 (Box 37)
- Knollwood Baptist Church (Box 37)
- Knoxville 3/7-8/1992 (Church Street United Methodist Church) (Box 37)
- The Land in Tanakh by Walter Harrelson (Box 37)
- Harrelson Lecture – MTSU, 4/2/92 (Box 37)
- Smith Lectures- Mercer, 4/7-8/92 (Box 37)
- NABPR- President’s Address, 11/21/93 (Box 37)
- Review Article- New Adam Sewanee Theological Review (Box 37)
- 6/12-14/92 New Orleans- Trinity Church Episcopal (Box 37)
- NRSV- Papers and Lectures (Box 37)
- Origins of Bible- Mar- Apr 1993 Westminster Church (Box 37)
- Orlando- Alum. (Mid-Florida Vanderbilt Club), 5/13/91 (Box 37)
- Oxford Companion to the Bible (Box 37)